Austin Jones

Software Engineer

New Orleans, LA

(504) 957-4814 | austin@austinjones.io LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a professional Software Engineer specializing in JavaScript. I am confident across the full-stack. I am proficient in Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js, and PostgreSQL. I am also competent in front-end technologies such as React, CSS3, and HTML5. I strive to incorporate my customer service skills in my development career.

SKILLS

Back End: Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js, PostgreSQL

Front End: JavaScript ES6, React.js, React Hooks, HTML5, CSS3, SASS

Additional Skills: Unit testing, Mocha, Chai, Vercel, Heroku, Git, GitHub, DBeaver, Node Package Manager (NPM)

PROJECTS

Periodic Tables (Restaurant Reservation System) | Repo | Production

- Designed and implemented a PostgreSQL database with relational schema to interconnect the application.
- Using Node.js, Express.js, and Knex.js, I built a RESTful API to transport data between application and database.
- SPA frontend web application implemented with React.js and Twitter Bootstrap. Implemented React Hooks and State Management to keep the displays on the site in-sync with changes to the database.

WeLoveMovies (Movie Review Database and API) | Repo

- Implemented a PostgreSQL database using Knex.js.
- Built a multi-router RESTful API using Express and Knex to create, read, update, and delete entries.
- The technology stack used includes Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js, PostgreSQL, and JS ES6.

Flashcard-O-Matic (Creating, Editing, Studying, and Deleting Decks and Cards) | Repo

- Designed and built a front-end SPA application using React.js in which you can create and study decks and their cards.
- Called and handled API responses to determine the content of the state of components.
- The technology stack used includes React.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and NPM.

EXPERIENCE

PRIVATE SECURITY SUPERVISOR

Rollo Security Services, Inc. | Garyville, LA

August 2020 – January 2021

• Coordinated security plans with clients to protect \$60 billion in assets and personnel.

PRIVATE SECURITY SUPERVISOR

Pinnacle Security and Investigation, Inc. | New Orleans, LA

March 2020 – August 2020

Protected the lives and belongings of over 200 people at a homeless shelter.

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Southeastern Louisiana University | Hammond, LA

August 2018 - December 2018

• Assisted Dr. Bonnie Achee by tutoring fellow students on algorithm design in Java.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSION CERTIFICATE

January 2021 - June 2021

Thinkful

- Worked with other engineering students immersively in an online remote environment to create responsive, dynamic web applications.
- Learned about the PERN stack, which includes: PostgreSQL, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js.
- Other technologies learned include Knex.js, Mocha & Chai, Jest, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.